Umar Adamu



umaralfaruq02@gmail.com



08140099331



linkedin.com/in/faruq-alkali

Summary

Graduate of Computer Science and a Software Engineer with Experience in System Analysis and Design, Data Structures & Algorithms, Collaboration tools, Penetration Testing, and Research. Skilled in Django Framework, Java, JavaScript, and Python Programming Language. I am a strong human resources professional and Community/Program manager for more than 5 years. I have vast experience in Software development and Testing. I frequently work with web development tools, Linux, SQL/MySQL, GCP, Postman, CI/CD, Redux, React/ React Native, and Firebase.

Experience



Software Engineer

GridHall Limited

Aug 2022 - Present (1 year 3 months)



Lead Organizer

Google Developers Group

Feb 2021 - Present (2 years 9 months)

As the lead organizer of GDG Yola, I facilitate the growth of the community in terms of numbers, engagements, opportunities and most of all, Learning ability.



Software Engineer

Bitpoint Inc.

Feb 2021 - Aug 2022 (1 year 7 months)

I take part in the design process and implementation of systems owned by the company, and developing and maintaining systems for our clients.



隊 Quality Assurance Engineer

Upgraded Era

Sep 2020 - Aug 2022 (2 years)

At UE, we provide Cyber Security & Testing Services to companies. Our clients include MTN Nigeria whom we offer testing services on their products and services then write a comprehensive report and suggest recommendations.



Managing Director

Bitpoint Inc.

Jul 2018 - Aug 2022 (4 years 2 months)

As the Manager, The day to day activities of the company is my responsibility to oversee and to ensure that the company is on track and setting up an accommodating work environment for our staff.

Training Facilitator

Andela

2018 - Jan 2022 (4 years)

I facilitated the beneficiaries of the Google Africa Developer Scholarship(Android Track) and ensured that they understood what they were learning.

Intern

FlexiSAF Edusoft Limited

Mar 2017 - Jan 2018 (11 months)

I was introduced to Django Web Framework during this internship and utilized the opportunity to improve my Java skill as well through their well equipped developers.

Education

Modibbo Adama University of Technology Yola, Adamawa State

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Computer Science Sep 2015 - Sep 2021

Preview Institute of Technology

Middle School Diploma, Computer Software and Media Applications Sep 2014 - Aug 2015

University Secondary School Yola

Senior School Certificate of Education, Sciences May 2009 - Sep 2014

University Primary School, Yola.

Primary Certificate Feb 2002 - Oct 2008

Licenses & Certifications

Certificate of Mentorship - Django Girls

G Google Digital Skills for Africa - Google

Mastering React Certificate - Code With Mosh cert_jl1p1gxp

Django Development Course Certificate - Code With Mosh cert_v1dxlr7d

The Ultimate React Native Series: Advanced Concepts - Code With Mosh

- Technical Support Fundamentals Coursera

 QPCXN92BL2KR
- The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking Coursera WXHADTW52KEK
- Operating Systems and You: Becoming a Power User Coursera LZBK6HHPEPWW
- CompTIA Cybersecurity Analyst (CySA+) Cisco
- Certificate of National Service National Youth Service Corps

Skills

Java • Python (Programming Language) • Django • Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) • Program Management • Analytical Skills • Information Technology • Quality Assurance • Research • Web Development

Honors & Awards

- **B.Tech** Modibbo Adama University of Technology Yola Sep 2021
- President Nigeria Association of Computer Science Students
 May 2017